[
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "the curly brackets",
		"back": "le parenthese graffe",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 16:12:47",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and what I did here",
		"back": "e quello che ho fatto qui",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 16:10:06",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "specify your filters",
		"back": "specifichi i tuoi filtri",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 16:08:40",
		"extras": "pr=speh-CHEE-fee-kee"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and in reality",
		"back": "e in realtà",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 14:13:46",
		"extras": "pr=ray-AHL-tah"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and what I want to do",
		"back": "e quello che voglio fare",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 13:08:45",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "but it was just wrapped in a box",
		"back": "ma è stato appena avvolto in una scatola",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 12:59:16",
		"extras": "pr=SCAH-toh-lah"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "that comes out of this box",
		"back": "che esce da questa scatola",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 12:52:49",
		"extras": "EH-shay"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "in case you haven't seen this show yet",
		"back": "nel caso in cui non hai ancora visto questo programma",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:48:45",
		"extras": "pr=KAH-zoh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "depending on the context",
		"back": "a seconda del contesto",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:28:18",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "if you click on this link",
		"back": "se clicchi su questo link",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:24:42",
		"extras": "pr=KLEE-kee"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "as I said before",
		"back": "come ho detto prima",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:23:23",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "what is relevant to you",
		"back": "ciò che il rilevante per te",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:20:16",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and since you would be connecting to a system",
		"back": "e poiché ti connetteresti a un sistema",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:17:55",
		"extras": "poh-ee-KAY"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "if you've done all of this",
		"back": "se hai fatto tutto questo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:13:44",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "when you visit the page",
		"back": "i quando visiti la pagina",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:11:34",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "you may not have access",
		"back": "potresti non avere accesso",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:05:20",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "that are required of us",
		"back": "che ci sono richiesti",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:03:03",
		"extras": "ree-kee-ESS-tee"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "first of all, you need to install the software",
		"back": "prima di tutto, devi installare il software",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:01:43",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "if you try to use Linux",
		"back": "se provi a usare Linux",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 10:00:04",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "make sure you look",
		"back": "assicurati di guardare",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 09:58:32",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "so first of all",
		"back": "quindi, prima di tutto",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 09:57:11",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and then on top of this component",
		"back": "e poi in cima a questo componente",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 09:55:15",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "which I was referring to previously",
		"back": "a cui mi riferivo in precedenza",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 09:49:13",
		"extras": "pr=pray-chay-DENT-sa"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "needed to make it work",
		"back": "necessari per farlo funzionare",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 09:45:25",
		"extras": "pr=nay-chess-SAR-ee"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "if you are new",
		"back": "se sei nuovo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 09:34:26",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "the first reason I chose",
		"back": "la prima ragione che cui ho scelto",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 09:31:09",
		"extras": "pr=rah-JOH-nay;pr=SHEL-toh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "which in my case",
		"back": "che nel mio caso",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 09:29:55",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "knowledge that is required",
		"back": "conoscenza che è richiesta",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 09:29:04",
		"extras": "koh-noh-SHENT-sa"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "why are you doing this",
		"back": "perché lo stai facendo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 00:40:41",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "but on the other hand",
		"back": "ma d'altra parte",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 00:37:13",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "but more similar to",
		"back": "ma più simile a",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 00:35:52",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and then you can just push the data",
		"back": "e poi puoi semplicemente spingere i dati",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 00:32:41",
		"extras": "pr=SPIN-jerr-ray"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "it would be really hard to do",
		"back": "sarebbe davvero difficile da fare",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 00:27:16",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "know any language",
		"back": "conoscere alcun linguaggio",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-17 22:54:44",
		"extras": "pr=ko-NOH-sher-ay;pr=leen-GWAH-joh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "so I was pretty familiar with this",
		"back": "quindi ero abbastanza familiare con questo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-17 22:50:51",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "because it is a part of a kit",
		"back": "poiché si un tratto di un kit",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-17 22:44:43",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "that you can see on the screen",
		"back": "che puoi vedere sullo schermo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-17 22:37:41",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "most of my other videos",
		"back": "la maggior parte dei miei altri video",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-17 22:32:59",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "GitLab provides us with some variables",
		"back": "GitLab nos proporciona algunas variables",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will return to our project",
		"back": "volveremos a nuestro proyecto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "for everything else",
		"back": "para todo lo demás",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I saved that earlier",
		"back": "lo guardé antes",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it's right here",
		"back": "está justo aquí",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we need to allow the user to upload files",
		"back": "necesitamos permitir al usuario cargar archivos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will need to add some permissions",
		"back": "necesitaremos agregar algunos permisos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and we will have to check this box",
		"back": "y tendremos que marcar esta casilla",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and then scroll down and then back up",
		"back": "y luego desplácese hacia abajo y luego hacia arriba",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you can repeat the steps",
		"back": "puedes repetir los pasos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you'll want to copy this password",
		"back": "querrás copiar esta contraseña",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you will have to regenerate it",
		"back": "tendrás de regenerarlo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "make sure you save them because otherwise you will lose them",
		"back": "asegúrate de guardarlos porque de lo contrario los perderás",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I am going to use it to paste some text into the input box",
		"back": "voy a usarlo para pegar algo de texto en el cuadro de entrada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "just follow exactly what I do and you should be fine",
		"back": "solo sigue exactamente lo que hago y deberías estar bien",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we didn't do anything with it",
		"back": "no hicimos nada con él",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and I will delete some of these comments",
		"back": "y borraré algunos de estos comentarios",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it may be tempting to create",
		"back": "puede ser tentador crear",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's go back",
		"back": "regresemos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I got to this page by browsing",
		"back": "llegué a esta página navegando",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so we can move on",
		"back": "así que podemos seguir adelante",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "something starts to happen",
		"back": "algo comienza a suceder",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "below the image",
		"back": "debajo de la imagen",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so let's take a look",
		"back": "así que echemos un vistazo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that investment will pay for itself many times over",
		"back": "esa inversión amortizará muchos veces",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it would be nice to find out",
		"back": "sería bueno averiguarlo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the next level",
		"back": "el siguiente nivel",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "each layer of testing",
		"back": "cada capa de prueba",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if you have ever seen a documentary",
		"back": "si alguna vez has visto un documental",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it's pretty easy to find out",
		"back": "es bastante fácil averiguar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "due to the delta",
		"back": "debido al delta",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "both approaches",
		"back": "ambos enfoques",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "pr. 1930",
		"back": "meel NOH-vay see-EN-troh TRAYN-tah",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in the last century",
		"back": "en el siglo pasado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "click on the tab",
		"back": "haga clic en la pestaña",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will not cover in this course",
		"back": "no cubriremos en este curso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "take a couple of minutes and",
		"back": "tómate un par de minutos y",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a branch called main",
		"back": "una rama llamada main",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a couple of things I want to point out",
		"back": "un par de cosas que quiero señalar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will leave these unset",
		"back": "dejaremos estos sin establecer",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "work back and forth",
		"back": "trabajar de un lado de otro",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the other thing that happens",
		"back": "la otra cosa que sucede",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I'm testing a hunch",
		"back": "pruebo una corazonada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "testing a hunch",
		"back": "probando una corazonada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "app developer",
		"back": "desarrollador de aplicaciones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is because it is very difficult to distinguish",
		"back": "esto se debe a que es muy difícil distinguir",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it is assumed that",
		"back": "se supone que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this concept helps to emphasize",
		"back": "Este concepto ayuda a enfatizar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's drink to software development",
		"back": "brindemos por el desarrollo de software",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "[day-sah-ROY-yoh]"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it consists of the following parts",
		"back": "es consta de las siguientes partes",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "[see-g|ee-EN-tays]"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so let's take a look at the general process",
		"back": "así que echemos un vistazo el proceso general",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "continuous delivery",
		"back": "entrega continua",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to a large extent",
		"back": "en gran medida",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "so we are all ready",
		"back": "quindi siamo tutti pronti",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-03 07:47:34",
		"extras": "pr=[pronti like \"own\"]"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "so this will activate our virtual environment",
		"back": "quindi questo attiverà il nostro ambiente virtuale",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-03 07:41:32",
		"extras": "conj=attivare; attiverà = futuro simplice"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "let's fix this",
		"back": "correggiamo questo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-03 07:26:06",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and to activate it",
		"back": "e per attivarlo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-03 07:22:45",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "each project",
		"back": "ciascun progetto",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-02 16:46:37",
		"extras": "pr=chass-KOON"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "this means you will be able to submit your data",
		"back": "ciò significa che sarai in grado di inviare i tuoi dati",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-02 07:56:41",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "this form collects information",
		"back": "questo modulo raccoglie informazioni",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-02 07:48:46",
		"extras": "pr=rah-KOH-lee-eh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and I'll leave you enough space",
		"back": "e ti lascerò abbastanza spazio",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-02 07:46:50",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "physical exercise",
		"back": "l'esercizio fisico",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-02 07:43:43",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "during the course, we will build a project",
		"back": "durante il corso, costruiremo un progetto",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-02 07:41:44",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "for science projects",
		"back": "per i progetti di scienza",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-01 09:36:19",
		"extras": "pr=SHENT-sa"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "where each framework excels",
		"back": "dove eccelle ogni framework",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-01 09:25:56",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "it's light, keeps the core simple",
		"back": "è leggero, mantiene el nucleo semplice",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-01 08:17:17",
		"extras": "pr=leh-JER-oh; pr=SEM-plih-cheh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "right for your project",
		"back": "giusto per il tuo progetto",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-01 08:14:54",
		"extras": "pr=[JOOS-toh]"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "sono entrambi framework popolari",
		"back": "they are both popular frameworks",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-01 08:09:56",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "so why choose Flask",
		"back": "allora perché scegliere Flask",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 17:43:59",
		"extras": "pr=sheh-lee-AIR-eh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "check out the documentation",
		"back": "dai un'occhiata alla documentazione",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 17:39:59",
		"extras": "pr=oon-oh-key-AH-ta"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "on a large scale",
		"back": "su larga scala",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 17:38:49",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "with just a few lines",
		"back": "con solo poche righe",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 17:36:52",
		"extras": "pr=POH-keh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "as your project grows",
		"back": "mentre il tuo progetto cresce",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 17:26:26",
		"extras": "pr=CRAY-sha"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "Flask can handle it all",
		"back": "Flask è in grado di gestire tutto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 16:49:36",
		"extras": "pr=jess-TEER-eh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "you can add",
		"back": "puoi aggiungere",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 16:43:20",
		"extras": "pr=[poo-OH-ee ah-JOON-jer-eh]"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "five lines of code",
		"back": "cinque righe di codice",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 16:42:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "here are some key features of Flask",
		"back": "ecco alcune caratteristiche chiave di Flask",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 16:37:55",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "this means you can decide",
		"back": "ciò significa che puoi decidere",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 16:30:23",
		"extras": "pr=[chow, kay, POH-ee, day-CHEE-deh-reh]"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "it's light, easy",
		"back": "è leggero, facile",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 16:16:06",
		"extras": "pr=[leh-JEH-oh FAH-chee-lay\t]"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "if you can write",
		"back": "se sei in grado di scrivere",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 15:31:35",
		"extras": "pr=[seh SAY]; pr=SKREE-veh-reh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "here's what I recommend",
		"back": "ecco cosa ti consiglio",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 15:21:19",
		"extras": "pr=con-SEE-leeoh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "it's pretty simple",
		"back": "è piuttosto semplice",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 15:13:42",
		"extras": "pr=[eh pee-oo-TOH-sto SEM-plih-cheh]"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "in this course",
		"back": "in questo corso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-31 14:53:30",
		"extras": "pr=KWEH-stoh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "code changes",
		"back": "modifiche al codice",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 08:20:07",
		"extras": "moh-DEE-fee-keh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "let's take a look at how you can do it",
		"back": "diamo un'occhiata a come puoi farlo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 08:20:01",
		"extras": "pr=oon-oh-key-AH-tah;conj=dare;diamo = let's give / we give;rule: drop final \"e\", so fare + lo becomes farlo"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "here are the options you have",
		"back": "ecco le opzioni che hai",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 20:19:28",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "we have already seen",
		"back": "abbiamo già visto",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 20:17:32",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "this can cause problems",
		"back": "ciò puo causare problemi",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 19:29:05",
		"extras": "pr=choh-POO-oh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "Git provides a setting",
		"back": "Git fornisce un'impostazione",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 19:16:27",
		"extras": "pr=for-NEE-shay"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "they use both a carriage return and a line feed",
		"back": "loro utilizzano sia un ritorno a capo che un line feed",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 19:14:01",
		"extras": "rank=4.95"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "but it's just nice to know",
		"back": "ma è solo bello saperlo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 17:00:09",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "you can do things like use two asterisks",
		"back": "puoi fare cose come usare due asterischi",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 16:57:18",
		"extras": "pr=puh-OY;pr=ah-stair-REE-skee;conj=potere"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "this means",
		"back": "ciò significa",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 16:52:41",
		"extras": "pr=CHOH"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "so anywhere inside our working directory",
		"back": "quindi ovunque all'interno della nostra directory lavoro",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 16:41:42",
		"extras": "pr=oh-VUN-kway"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "these lines",
		"back": "queste righe",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 16:37:47",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "at the same time",
		"back": "allo stesso tempo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 14:59:36",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "that you might use",
		"back": "che potresti usare",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 14:45:23",
		"extras": "conj=potere; potresti = conditional"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "easy for your team",
		"back": "facile per il tuo team",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 14:41:52",
		"extras": "pr=FACH-ee-lay"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "as we will see in a minute",
		"back": "come vedremo tra un minuto",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 08:25:15",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "those files need to be saved",
		"back": "quei file devono essere salvati",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 08:20:17",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "they will commit the file",
		"back": "eseguiranno il commit del file",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 08:15:22",
		"extras": "pr=eh-zeh-gwee-RAH-noh;conj=eseguire;eseguire = to execute"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "so in this scenario",
		"back": "quindi in questo scenario",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 08:12:39",
		"extras": "pr=sheh-NAR-ee-oh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "this may cause commits to be overwritten",
		"back": "ciò può causare la sovrascrittura dei commit",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 08:10:40",
		"extras": "pr=chow-POO-oh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "one of the mistakes you need to watch out for",
		"back": "uno degli errori a cui devi fare attenzione",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 08:06:36",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "we have made our commit",
		"back": "abbiamo fatto il nostro commit",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 01:28:41",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "their changes",
		"back": "le loro modifiche",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 00:59:16",
		"extras": "pr=moh-DEE-fee-keh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "they open the file with vim",
		"back": "aprono il file con vim",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 00:57:19",
		"extras": "conj=aprire"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "user two would also like to edit the file",
		"back": "l'utente due vorrebbe anche modificare il file",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-09 00:54:05",
		"extras": "conj=volere; vorrebbe = conditional"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and it's pretty simple",
		"back": "e piuttosto semplice",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-08 21:16:55",
		"extras": "pr=SEM-plee-chay"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "in this scenario",
		"back": "in questo scenario",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-08 21:06:39",
		"extras": "pr=sheh-NAH-ree-oh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "with their team",
		"back": "con il loro team",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-08 21:05:31",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "keep this in mind",
		"back": "tienilo a mente",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 22:30:28",
		"extras": "conj=tenere; tieni = imperative/present"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "one more thing i should point out",
		"back": "un'altra cosa che dovrei sottolineare",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 22:26:50",
		"extras": "conj=dovere; dovrei = conditional"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "conj-potere-pres",
		"back": "posso, puoi, può, possiamo, potete, possono",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 22:20:04",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "your team can adopt",
		"back": "il tuo team può adottare",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 20:08:25",
		"extras": "conj=potere"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "from there, we'll talk about conventions",
		"back": "da lì, parleremo di convenzioni",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 20:04:28",
		"extras": "parleremo = futuro semplice;conj=parlare"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "some practices",
		"back": "alcune pratiche",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 20:03:07",
		"extras": "pr=PRAH-tee-kay"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "at this point",
		"back": "a questo punto",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 19:50:09",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "this chapter will focus on the basics",
		"back": "questo capitolo concentrerà sulla basi",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 19:45:55",
		"extras": "conj=concentrare"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "that this course provides you",
		"back": "che questo corso ti fornisca",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 00:17:52",
		"extras": "pr=for-NEE-skah"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "I will be there to guide you through every step",
		"back": "sarò lì per guidarti in ogni fase",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 00:12:05",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "if you understand these concepts",
		"back": "se capisci questi concetti",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 00:08:41",
		"extras": "pr=kah-PEE-shee"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "life cycle",
		"back": "ciclo di vita",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 00:01:03",
		"extras": "pr=CHEEK-loh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "I will guide you, step by step",
		"back": "ti guiderò passo dopo passo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-05 03:13:52",
		"extras": "pr=gwee-dair-OH"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "we will guide you, step by step",
		"back": "guideremo, passo dopo passo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-05 03:13:33",
		"extras": "pr=gwee-dair-RAY-moh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "source code",
		"back": "codice sorgente",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-05 03:09:35",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "easy to maintain",
		"back": "facili da mantenere",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 11:44:18",
		"extras": "pr=[FAH-chee-lee da man-ten-NAIR-eh]"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "software development",
		"back": "sviluppo del software",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 11:37:38",
		"extras": "pr=zvee-LOOP-oh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "in our programs",
		"back": "nei nostri programmi",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 11:39:12",
		"extras": "pr=nay"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I'll guide you through everything",
		"back": "voy a guiarte a través de todo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "on the side",
		"back": "en el costado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "for now, keep in mind that",
		"back": "por ahora, ten en cuenta que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "ten = tu, tenga = usted, conj=tener"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as a starting point",
		"back": "como punto de partida",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "why would we do that",
		"back": "por que haríamos eso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "hacer uses -har for future and conditional"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that sounds a little strange",
		"back": "eso suena un poco raro",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that will guide you through a simple tutorial",
		"back": "que te guiará a través de un tutorial sencillo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "conj=guiar; pr=gee-ahr-RAH"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "your name and surname",
		"back": "tu nombre y apellido",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=ah-pay-YEE-doh"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conf. pedir present",
		"back": "pido, pides, pide, pedimos, pedís, piden",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "rank=4.9"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conj. pedir preterite",
		"back": "pedí, pediste, pidió, pedimos, pidisteis, pidieron",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "rank=4.9"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I don't know what to do",
		"back": "no sé qué hacer",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "once you have created your account, do the following",
		"back": "una vez que hayas creado tu cuenta, haz lo siguiente",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "hayas = present perfect subjunctive, conj=crear, haz = tu, haga = usted"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conj. ver present",
		"back": "veo, ves, ve, vemos, veis, ven",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "rank=4.9"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conj. ver preterite",
		"back": "vi, viste, vio, vimos, visteis, vieron",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "rank=4.9"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so if you are ready",
		"back": "así que si estás listo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as your site grows",
		"back": "a medida que tu sitio crece",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "crecer = to grow, regular but you crezco"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "create your own work from scratch",
		"back": "crea tu propio trabajo desde cero",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "crea = tu, cree = usted"
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "once the download is complete",
		"back": "zodra de download is voltooid",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-22 18:57:39",
		"extras": "pr=FOHL-toyd"
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "can be incredibly useful",
		"back": "kan ongelooflijk nuttig zijn",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-22 18:56:39",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "but note that these are not supported",
		"back": "maar houd er rekening mee dat deze niet worden ondersteund",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-22 18:53:32",
		"extras": "pr=RAY-ken-ing; pr=DAY-zeh; pr=AHN-der-STOW-nt"
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "the type of hard drive",
		"back": "het type harde schijf",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-22 18:35:24",
		"extras": "pr=\"TEE-peh HAR-deh s*IGHF\""
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "a smooth experience",
		"back": "een soepele ervaring",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-22 18:08:41",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "first of all",
		"back": "ten eerste",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 21:59:29",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "depending on your equipment choices",
		"back": "afhankelijk van je apparatuurkeuzes",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 21:58:05",
		"extras": "pr=af-HAHN-kel-lik; pr=KÖZ-ess"
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "because it is maintained by a dedicated community",
		"back": "omdat het wordt onderhouden door een toegewijde gemeenschap",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 03:07:53",
		"extras": "pr=TOO-*eh-wigh-deh; pr=*eh-MAYN-s*ahp"
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "OBS can be used on both Apple and Windows",
		"back": "OBS kan worden gebruikt op zowel Apple en Windows",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 03:05:49",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "it is completely free to use",
		"back": "het is volledig gratis te gebruiken",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 03:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "let's get started",
		"back": "laten we aan de slag gaan",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 02:57:32",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "nl",
		"front": "to improve your broadcast",
		"back": "om je uitzending te verbeteren",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 02:56:13",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "so, in any case",
		"back": "quindi, in ogni caso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 18:32:06",
		"extras": "pr=OHN-yee-KAH-zoh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "so for example",
		"back": "quindi, ad esempio",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 18:29:07",
		"extras": "pr=ay-ZEM-pee-oh (not SEM)"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "but it's also very easy",
		"back": "ma è anche molto facile",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 18:27:32",
		"extras": "pr=FAH-chee-lay"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "Therefore",
		"back": "quindi",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 17:47:04",
		"extras": "pr=QUEEN-dee"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "of fundamental networking concepts",
		"back": "dei concetti fondamentali di rete",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 17:43:36",
		"extras": "pr=day-kon-CHET-tee; pr=RAY-teh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and finally",
		"back": "e infine",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 17:42:03",
		"extras": "pr=in-FEE-nah"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "that you knew",
		"back": "che tu conoscessi",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 17:37:47",
		"extras": "pr=kon-oh-SHEH-see"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and at the end of the course",
		"back": "e alla fine del corso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 17:28:03",
		"extras": "pr=KOR'-soh (not zoh)"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "in recent years",
		"back": "negli ultimi anni",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 17:23:50",
		"extras": "pr=nehleeoo-tee-mee"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "for React developers",
		"back": "per gli sviluppatori di React",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 17:25:27",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and for this reason",
		"back": "e per questo motivo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 17:26:10",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "surgical modifications",
		"back": "modifiche chirurgiche",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:45:34",
		"extras": "pr=keer-RUHR-gee-keh"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "by the way",
		"back": "a proposito",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:42:56",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "you can see it still appears here",
		"back": "puoi vedere che appare ancora qui",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:42:04",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "without the emojis",
		"back": "senza gli emoji",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:40:41",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "at the top of this list",
		"back": "in cima a questo elenco",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:38:18",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "you can choose the school",
		"back": "puoi scegliere la scuola",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:34:49",
		"extras": "pr=SHEH-lih-ray"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "shorter or longer",
		"back": "più corta o più lunga",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:31:59",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "the length",
		"back": "la lunghezza",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:30:29",
		"extras": "pr=loong-GEH-tsa"
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "right here",
		"back": "proprio qui",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:29:20",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "the area on the left works pretty much the same as normal",
		"back": "l'area a sinistra funziona più o meno come il normale",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:28:38",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "when you use the arrows",
		"back": "quando usi le frecce",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:25:51",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "after the first title",
		"back": "dopo il primo titolo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:19:37",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "it contains a preview of the results",
		"back": "contiene un anteprima dei risultati",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:14:26",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "it was a long text",
		"back": "era un testo lungo",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:05:06",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "the same prompt",
		"back": "lo stesso prompt",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:04:34",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "first, it will create a new chat",
		"back": "per prima cosa, creerà una nuova chat",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 21:03:34",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "and now more than ever",
		"back": "e ora più che mai",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-13 20:40:58",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "it can be executed",
		"back": "può essere eseguito",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-18 23:50:05",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "check it out",
		"back": "compruébalo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "security and storage",
		"back": "seguridad y almacenamiento",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we want to add authentication",
		"back": "queremos agregar autenticación",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "but above all I hope this has been useful",
		"back": "pero sobre todo espero que esto haya sido ùtil",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "anyway, please give it a like so more people can see it",
		"back": "de todos modos, dale me gusta para que más personas lo vean",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is something you should keep in mind",
		"back": "esto es algo que debes tener en cuenta",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this means that it can handle any character",
		"back": "esto significa que puede manejar cualquier carácter",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the good news is that ink has no limitations",
		"back": "la buena noticia es que ink no tiene limitaciones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as the story grows, you may want to do things",
		"back": "a medida que la historia crece, es posible que desees hacer cosas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the variable cannot be changed after it has been declared for the first time",
		"back": "la variable no se puede cambiar después de haber sido declarada por primera vez",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "next, let's add a variable",
		"back": "a continuación, agreguemos una variable",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "there is nothing more to show",
		"back": "no hay nada más que mostrar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as you may have guessed",
		"back": "como habrás adivinado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is because we need to activate it",
		"back": "esto se debe a que necesitamos activarlo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the text does not yet appear in the story",
		"back": "el texto todavía no aparece en la historia",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if you go to the drop-down menu on the top left",
		"back": "si vas al menu desplegable en la parte superior izquierda",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will go to a new line",
		"back": "iremos a una nueva línea",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to take a step back",
		"back": "para retroceder un paso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "once downloaded, you can start the program",
		"back": "una vez descargado, puedes iniciar el programa",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "it",
		"front": "for your Python projects",
		"back": "per i tuoi progetti Python",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so let's take a look at the readme file",
		"back": "así que echemos un vistazo al archivo readme",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a very common thing to do",
		"back": "algo muy común que se puede hacer",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's change it to no",
		"back": "combiémoslo a no",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so we need to provide that name",
		"back": "por lo que debemos proporcionar ese nombre",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "what this function is about and what it does",
		"back": "qué se trata esta función y qué hace",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I like that standard because",
		"back": "me gusta esa estandár porque",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is how you do it",
		"back": "así es como lo hace",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let me save it",
		"back": "déjeme guardarlo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I'll explain it to you a little later",
		"back": "explicártelo un poco más adelante",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the file will be overwritten",
		"back": "el archivo se sobrescribirá",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to a large extent",
		"back": "en gran medida",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this process will take some time",
		"back": "este proceso tardará un tiempo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so that it is capable",
		"back": "para que sea capaz",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as we see, the binaries will be generated",
		"back": "como vemos, se va a generar los binarios",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "having built it on our machine",
		"back": "al haberlo construido en nuestra máquina",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "Go stands out for the small size of its binaries",
		"back": "Go destaca por el pequeño tamaño de sus binarios",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since we would be forcing him to install Go",
		"back": "puesto que le estaríamos obligando a instalar Go [gr. present conditional]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "but we can't deliver it to the user like this",
		"back": "pero no podemos entregarla así al usuario",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's start with a small application",
		"back": "partamos de una pequeña aplicación",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in which they are going to be executed",
		"back": "en el que se vayan a ejecutar [gr. subjunctive present]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we usually run our programs directly from the source code",
		"back": "solemos ejecutar nuestros programas directamente desde el código fuente",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "common tasks such as counting requests",
		"back": "tareas comunes como el conteo de peticiones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we should see the message",
		"back": "deberíamos ver el mensaje [gr. present conditional]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this time, we should get the correct answer",
		"back": "esta vez, deberíamos recibir la respuesta correcta [gr. present conditional]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as expected, we have an error",
		"back": "como era de esperar, tenemos un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "whenever we returned an error previously",
		"back": "siempre que devolviéramos un error anteriormente [gr. subjunctive imperfect 1]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will leave these set as they are",
		"back": "dejaremos estos configurados como están",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in order to save it",
		"back": "para guardarlo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I will save that later",
		"back": "lo guardaré más tarde",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it's right there",
		"back": "está justo ahí",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as dark as it can be",
		"back": "tan oscuro como puede ser",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "click on the button",
		"back": "haga clic en el botón",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "click on the left side",
		"back": "haga clic en el lado izquierdo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "on the one hand",
		"back": "por un lado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since we consider it an error",
		"back": "puesto que lo consideramos un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will return an error",
		"back": "retornaremos un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the information passes through our web layer before being sent to the server",
		"back": "la información pasa por nuestra capa web antes de ser enviada al servidor",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "including the value",
		"back": "incluyendo el valor",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the time that has elapsed",
		"back": "el tiempo que ha transcurrido",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the first thing it does is get the current time",
		"back": "lo primero que hace es obtener la hora actual",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that is in charge of counting the requests",
		"back": "que se encargue de contar las peticiones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that is in charge of counting the requests",
		"back": "que se encargue de contar las peticiones [en-KAR-gay]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "although we could have used any other",
		"back": "aunque podríamos haber utilizado cualquier otro",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we access the URL",
		"back": "accedemos a la URL",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "start the server on port 8080",
		"back": "arranca el servidor en el puerto 8080",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in isolation",
		"back": "de manera aislada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "will make a request",
		"back": "hará una petition",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it will return the list",
		"back": "devolverá la lista",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to test it",
		"back": "para probarlo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "finally",
		"back": "por último",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's ask",
		"back": "vamos a pedir",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I will store in the variable",
		"back": "almacenaré en la variable",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "he copies text in all at once, he doesn't type it",
		"back": "copia el texto de una sola vez, no lo escribe",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "by prompt we understand",
		"back": "entendemos por prompt",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you can see on the last line",
		"back": "puedes verlo en la última línea",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will read the answer",
		"back": "leeremos la respuesta",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the root directory",
		"back": "el directorio raíz",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will return to the subject",
		"back": "volveremos al tema",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which is responsible for making the request to the API",
		"back": "que se engarga de hacer la petición a la API",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in the following videos",
		"back": "en siguientes vídeos [see-g|ee-EN-tays]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "wouldn't it be better to be able to do something like this",
		"back": "no sería mejor ser capaces de hacer algo así",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "tens, hundreds",
		"back": "decenas, cientos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "text box",
		"back": "caja de texto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the mouse",
		"back": "el ratón",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "via our browser",
		"back": "mediante nuestro navegador",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "how can we see all the messages",
		"back": "cómo podemos hacer para ver todos los mensajes",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since the goroutine might not have enough time",
		"back": "ya que la gorutina podría no tener tiempo suficiente",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the keyword go",
		"back": "la palabra clave go",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to perform tasks in the background",
		"back": "para realizar tareas en segundo plano",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in a single thread of execution",
		"back": "en un solo hilo de ejecución",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "just once, as we expected",
		"back": "una única vez, como esperábamos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we can ensure that",
		"back": "podemos asegurarnos que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is because",
		"back": "esto se debe a que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that has the protections inside",
		"back": "que dentro tiene las protecciones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a counter and a container //comparison",
		"back": "un contador y un contenedor",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "he works like a teacher but he doesn't know how to solve this problem //comparison",
		"back": "él trabaja como profesor pero no sabe cómo solucionar este problema",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we see how to use",
		"back": "vemos cómo utilizar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a shared resource",
		"back": "un recurso compartido",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a set of primitives",
		"back": "un conjunto de primitivas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "instead of writing this code",
		"back": "en lugar de escribir este código",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "expensive operations",
		"back": "operaciones costosas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "expensive operations",
		"back": "operaciones costosas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a single thread",
		"back": "un solo hilo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this way we can make sure that all goroutines have finished",
		"back": "de esta manera, podemos asegurarnos que todas las gorutinas hayan finalizado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "an integer value",
		"back": "un valor entero",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the shared resource can be a variable",
		"back": "el recurso compartido puede ser una variable",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "race conditions",
		"back": "condiciones de carrera",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as it can lead to over coupling",
		"back": "ya que puede llevar a un acoplamiento excesivo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the only one that fails",
		"back": "el único que falla",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "after which the context will be cancelled",
		"back": "tras el cual se cancelerá el contexto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the text string",
		"back": "la cadena de texto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's make sure that",
		"back": "vamos a aseguarnos que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "when this time is up",
		"back": "cuando se cumpla este tiempo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "note=cumplir: to fulfill"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "thirty, forty, fifty, sixty, seventy, eighty, ninety",
		"back": "treinta, cuarenta, cincuenta, sesenta, setenta, ochenta, noventa",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the breakfast, the lunch, the dinner",
		"back": "el desayuno, el almuerzo, la cena",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's look at this with different examples",
		"back": "veámoslo con diferentes ejemplos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which begins when it is created",
		"back": "que comienza cuando se crea",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "freeing up resources if necessary",
		"back": "liberando recursos si fuera necesario [gr. subjunctive imperfect 1]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "being able to define a time to cancel the operation",
		"back": "pudiendo definir un tiempo para cancelar la operación",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as we have seen",
		"back": "como hemos visto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the variable will have been modified",
		"back": "la variable habrá sido modificada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "will be applied to the struct",
		"back": "se aplicarán a la struct",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this pointer will point to the memory address of the value",
		"back": "este puntero apuntará a la dirección de memoria del valor",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's store the value 17",
		"back": "vamos a almacenar el valor 17",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "an integer value",
		"back": "un valor de tipo entero",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "leaving the code much cleaner",
		"back": "quedando el código mucho más limpio",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's see this in an example",
		"back": "veámoslo con un ejemplo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if there is any error",
		"back": "si hubiera algún error [gr. subjunctive imperfect 1]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "each of which modifies a field",
		"back": "cada una de las cuales modifica un campo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a function that receives a pointer",
		"back": "una función que recibe un puntero",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which value corresponds to which field",
		"back": "qué valor corresponde a qué campo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if we were to add new fields",
		"back": "si añadiésimos nuevos campos [gr. subjunctive imperfect 2]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "its wide range of packages",
		"back": "su amplia gama de paquetes",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "Go places a strong emphasis on testing",
		"back": "Go pone un fuerte énfasis en las pruebas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "digital signatures",
		"back": "firmas digitales",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the library provides many useful tools",
		"back": "la librería proporciona muchas herramientas útiles",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to a large extent",
		"back": "en gran medida",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "high performance",
		"back": "alto rendimiento",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the library is highly optimized",
		"back": "la librería está altamente optimizada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "file management",
		"back": "manejo de archivos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "above the current package",
		"back": "por encima del paquete actual",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in such a way that",
		"back": "de tal modo que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "higher layers of the application",
		"back": "capas más altas de la aplicación",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "therefore",
		"back": "por tanto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "below it",
		"back": "por debajo de él",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "such as",
		"back": "tales como",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "deployment code",
		"back": "código despliegue [des-SPLEE-gay]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's look at it with a small example",
		"back": "veámoslo con un pequeño ejemplo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and finally, I want to highlight the test directory",
		"back": "y por último, quiero destacar el directorio de pruebas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "from outside the project",
		"back": "desde fuera del proyecto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "pr. cmd",
		"back": "[say ehm-MAY day]",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we can find it in the repository",
		"back": "podemos encontrarlo en el repositorio",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a set of organizational patterns",
		"back": "un conjunto de patrones de organización",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "our hierarchy",
		"back": "nuestra jerarquía",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which helps us",
		"back": "lo cual nos ayuda",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which is a mistake",
		"back": "lo cual es un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "although it seems to make sense",
		"back": "aunque parece tener sentido",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "for this reason",
		"back": "por ello",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in such a way that",
		"back": "de tal forma de",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "internal scope of the package",
		"back": "ámbito interno del paquete",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will have to expose the functions",
		"back": "tendremos que exponer las funciones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since it is an implementation detail",
		"back": "ya que es un detalle de implementación",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we are hiding it on purpose",
		"back": "lo estamos ocultando a propósito",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "place the files in that directory",
		"back": "colocar los archivos en ese directorio",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "code coverage",
		"back": "cobertura de código",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it's just the beginning",
		"back": "es solo el principio",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you will immerse yourself in the code",
		"back": "te sumergirás en el código",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "provide you with an understanding",
		"back": "brindarte una comprensión",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you are going to start",
		"back": "vas a empezar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "optimized performance",
		"back": "rendimiento optimizado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "new heights",
		"back": "nuevas alturas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "timed out",
		"back": "tiempo de espera agotado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "but if the connection was successful",
		"back": "pero si la conexión fuera exitosa",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "fuera = subjunctive imperfect; conj=ser"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we have the following server",
		"back": "tenemos el siguiente servidor",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it looks kind of weird",
		"back": "se ve medio raro",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we have been asked to return a client's information through a service",
		"back": "nos han solicitado devolver por medio de un servicio la information de una clienta",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "resource not found",
		"back": "recurso no encontrado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I'm going to go to my code",
		"back": "voy a irme a mi código",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if there was an error",
		"back": "si hubiera un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "each request that arrives on the route",
		"back": "cada solicitud que llegue a la ruta",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=YAY-gay"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "after this",
		"back": "luego de esto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the first thing we are going to do is",
		"back": "lo primero que vamos hacer es",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "add, subtract and multiply",
		"back": "sumar, restar y multiplicar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "do you know anything about it",
		"back": "sabes algo al respecto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's do the test",
		"back": "hagamos la prueba",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we look at how we can create a web server",
		"back": "vemos cómo podemos crear un servidor web",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a high performance web framework",
		"back": "un framework web de alto rendimiento",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if there was an error",
		"back": "si hubiera un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "conj=haber; hubiera = imperfect subjunctive of haber"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it allows you to format the output with indents",
		"back": "él permite formatear la salida con sangrías",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we send the query",
		"back": "enviamos la consulta",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's go to the code",
		"back": "vamos a irnos al código",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the information that comes in this parameter",
		"back": "la información que venga en esta parámetro",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "venga = subjunctive of venir; conj=venir"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "after the question mark",
		"back": "después del signo de pregunta",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "pr. alphabet, letters with standard pronunciations",
		"back": "a, b, c, d, e, _, _, _, i, _, k, _, _, _, _, o, p, q, _, _, t, u, _, _, _, _, _",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "pr. alphabet, letters with different pronuncations",
		"back": "f = EFF-ay, g = HEH, h = AH-chah, j = HOH-ta, l = ELL-ay, m = EM-ay, n = EN-ay, n = EN-yeh, r = ERR-ay, s = ESS-ay, v = OO-veh, w = oo-veh-DUB-lay, x = EK-ees, y = ee-grey-EGG-ah, z = SET-ah",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "each %v will be replaced by a value from our map",
		"back": "cada %v va a ser sustituido por un valor de nuestro mapa",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and our wish is to turn it into a string",
		"back": "y nuestro deseo es lo convertirlo en un string",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "divided into five groups separated by hyphens",
		"back": "divididos en cinco grupos separados por guiones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=gee-OH-nays"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we are going to go through the slice using a for loop",
		"back": "vamos a recorrer el slice por medio de un for",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so we want to remove it from the slice",
		"back": "por lo que deseamos lo eliminar del slice",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "conj=desear; deseamos is present desear, to wish, regular"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conj. dar present",
		"back": "doy das da damos dais dan",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conj.dar preterite",
		"back": "di diste dio dimos disteis dieron",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "however, we realized that Thursday is a holiday",
		"back": "sin embargo, nos dimos cuenta que el día jueves es feriado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "conj=dar; dimos is preterite of dar"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and I click on Send",
		"back": "y le doy clic en Enviar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "question=what does the \"le\" do here"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I make sure it is a POST method",
		"back": "me aseguro que sea un método POST",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's set the header",
		"back": "vamos a setear el header",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "where we indicate that there was an error",
		"back": "donde indicamos que hubo un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "hubo = preterite of haber; conj=haber"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "by means of an error",
		"back": "por medio de un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "but if everything is successful",
		"back": "pero si todo es exitoso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in case there was an error",
		"back": "en caso de que existiera un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "conj=existir, existiera = imperfect subjunctive of existir"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this helps us unpack the elements",
		"back": "esto nos ayuda a desempaquetar los elementos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to check if we saved the file",
		"back": "para comprobar si guardamos el archivo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "otherwise we will indicate that it does not exist",
		"back": "caso contrario vamos a indicar que no existe",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and in square brackets",
		"back": "y entre paréntesis cuadrados",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's see in the case of React",
		"back": "veamos en el caso de React",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "veamos = imperitive and subjunctive present"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conj. ver present",
		"back": "veo, ves, ve, vemos, veis, ven",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conj. ver preterite",
		"back": "vi viste vio vimos visteis vieron",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it has a name associated with it",
		"back": "tiene asociada un nombre",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "two integers",
		"back": "dos numeros enteros",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "what we are going to do is place an if-statement here",
		"back": "lo que vamos a hacer es colocar una declaración if aquí",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the last name",
		"back": "el apellido",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we may not remember the name",
		"back": "tal vez no recordemos el nombre",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "conj=recordar; recordemos is present subjunctive of recordar, regular but o\u003eue"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we subtract 1",
		"back": "le restamos 1",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's do that",
		"back": "hagamos eso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "hagamos = present subjunctive of hacer; conj=hacer"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we can do it through the index",
		"back": "lo podemos hacer por medio del índice",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since this will be the one to whom the prize will be awarded",
		"back": "dado que esta será al que se le entregue el premio",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "entregue = subjunctive present of entregar, almost regular (yo preterite: entregué); conj=entregar"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we have realized that there was a mistake",
		"back": "nos hemos dado cuenta que hubo un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "dar = dado, dando; hubo = preterite of haber; rank=4.92"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the winning numbers of a raffle",
		"back": "los números ganadores de una rifa",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "when you don't know the amount of arguments",
		"back": "cuando desconozcas la cantidad de argumentos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to loop through this string array",
		"back": "para recorrer este arreglo de string",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "rank=4.89"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in case it happens",
		"back": "en caso de que pase",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is because it may be possible that the string is not a valid number",
		"back": "esto se debe a que puede ser posible que la cadena no sea un número válido.",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this can be done to make the data compatible",
		"back": "eso se puede hacer para que los datos sean compatibles",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "sean = ser present subjuctive"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's hit Enter",
		"back": "vamos a darle Enter",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "\"le\" is just a filler pronoun"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "double quotes",
		"back": "las comillas dobles",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we place a backtick in front and at the end",
		"back": "colocamos un backtick adelante y al final",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "colocar = to place, almost regular, preterite: yo coloqué"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we have achieved our goal",
		"back": "hemos logrado nuestro objetivo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as part of the task",
		"back": "como parte de la tarea",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in the matter we have",
		"back": "en el asunto tenemos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we have been asked to send an email",
		"back": "nos han solicitado enviar un correo electrónico",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the solution to common challenges",
		"back": "la solución desafíos comunes",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "although you may have encountered challenges",
		"back": "aunque quizás te hayas encontrado con retos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "hayas = present perfect subjunctive"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you have doubts",
		"back": "te surgen dudas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "literally \"doubts emerge for you\", surgir = arise, emerge, appear"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "has it happened to you that while you are programming",
		"back": "te ha pasado que mientras estás programando",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we are indicating that",
		"back": "estamos indicando que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 21:45:15",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "with the time it has taken to be executed",
		"back": "con el tiempo que se ha demorado en ser ejecutado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 11:30:55",
		"extras": "conj=demorar; demorar = to delay, regular"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's calculate how long the request takes",
		"back": "vamos a calcular cuánto se demora la petición",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 11:24:06",
		"extras": "conj=demorar; demorar = to delay, regular"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "he must always do three things",
		"back": "el siempre debe hace tres cosas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 11:20:25",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this will be in charge of making the request",
		"back": "esta se va encargar de hacer la petición",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 11:06:36",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's implement it",
		"back": "vamos a implementarlo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 11:02:27",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since if the id is not found",
		"back": "ya que si no se encuentra el id",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 02:08:11",
		"extras": "pr=JAH-kay-see"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "where we are going to raise an exception",
		"back": "donde vamos a levantar una excepción",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 02:06:30",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the status codes that an API returns",
		"back": "los códigos de estado que una API retorna",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-21 01:58:38",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we can check it and it should bring us a list",
		"back": "lo podemos comprobar y este nos debería traer una lista",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-19 11:21:16",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "when we ran the server, a file called todo.db was created",
		"back": "cuando corrimos el servidor, se ha creado un archivo llamada todo.db",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-19 11:18:26",
		"extras": "conj=correr; corrimos = preterite; preterite for both -er and -ir verbs is -imos"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that we are labeling",
		"back": "que estamos etiquetando",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 10:47:08",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we are going to use the \"id\" key",
		"back": "vamos a usar la llave \"id\"",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 10:45:12",
		"extras": "pr=JAW-veh"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and no longer belongs to the default section",
		"back": "y que ya no pertenece a la sección default",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 10:37:56",
		"extras": "pr=ee-kay-JAW-noh"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "along with attribute we just defined",
		"back": "junto con atributo que acabamos de definir",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 10:24:32",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "with the help of tags",
		"back": "con la ayuda de los tags",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 10:14:06",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the quotation marks and the commas",
		"back": "las comillas y las comas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 19:08:56",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we leave the empty quotes",
		"back": "dejamos las comillas vacias",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 19:08:04",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that belong to them",
		"back": "que les pertenezcan",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 19:03:15",
		"extras": "conj=pertenecer; pertenezcan = present subjunctive (instead of present indicative: pertenecen)"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's remove the extra lines",
		"back": "vamos a quitar los líneas que sobran",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 18:55:25",
		"extras": "rank=4.8"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and we change app for router",
		"back": "y cambiamos app por router",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 18:52:55",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "indicates an error",
		"back": "señala un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 18:49:17",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "This, in turn, allows the project to be more organized",
		"back": "esto, a su vez, permite que el proyecto sea más organizado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-17 18:42:41",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since we can get metadata",
		"back": "puesto que podemos obtener metadatos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "instead of defining the file",
		"back": "en vez de definir el archivo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "delivers a 404 code",
		"back": "entrega una código 404",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the element associated with the file you want to upload",
		"back": "el elemento asociado al archivo que se quiere subir",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "whose name will be stored",
		"back": "cuyo nombre será almacenado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "storage service",
		"back": "servicio de almacenamiento",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since what we want to see is how it works",
		"back": "puesto que lo que queremos ver es su funcionamiento",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the function is going to be called",
		"back": "la función se va a llamar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we must wait for the instruction to be fulfilled",
		"back": "debemos esperar que la instrucción se cumple",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since the function only returns a dictionary",
		"back": "puesto que la función solo retorna un diccionario",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "puesto = past participle of poner (irregular); conj=poner"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "another may be being processed at the same time",
		"back": "otra puede estar siendo procesada al mismo tiempo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that has been created",
		"back": "que a sido creada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and therefore",
		"back": "y por ende",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in which it is placed",
		"back": "en el que se pone",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which is responsible for creating the elements",
		"back": "que se encarga de crear los elementos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to test the model",
		"back": "para probar el modelo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that is part of the body",
		"back": "que hace parte del body",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and add them to the list of items",
		"back": "y los agregue a la lista de elementos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "they usually receive data through the body",
		"back": "suelen recibir datos a través del body",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it is not always required that the request receives a body",
		"back": "no siempre es requerido que la petición recibe un body",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "who delivers the request to us",
		"back": "que nos entrega la petición",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "they should not be delivered by an endpoint",
		"back": "no deben ser entregadas por un endpoint",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "five hundred",
		"back": "quinientos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "these parameters come as part of the route",
		"back": "estos parámetros llegan como parte de la ruta",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it will be as if we had sent a None",
		"back": "será como hubiéramos enviado un None",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "conj=haber; hubiéramos = subjunctive imperfect"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if we leave it empty",
		"back": "si lo dejamos vacío",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "but we must write it",
		"back": "sino que debemos escribirlo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we no longer have options",
		"back": "ya no nos salen opciones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "conj=salen; salen = to leave, go out"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that have already been completed",
		"back": "que ya hayan sido completados",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=JAW-ha-jahn-SEE-doh"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "an assigned value",
		"back": "un valor asignado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "later in this course",
		"back": "más adelante en este curso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "neither of them meets the objective",
		"back": "ninguno de los dos cumple con el objetivo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "cumplir = to fulfill, carry out, reach (an age); conj=cumplir"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since this endpoint",
		"back": "ya que este endpoint",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=JAW-kay-ES-tah"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the endpoint allows the sending and receiving of data",
		"back": "el endpoint permite el envío y el recepción de datos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it is recommended to have a defined structure",
		"back": "se recomienda tener una estructura definida",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "conj=recomendar; recomienda = simple present"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since this documentation is interactive",
		"back": "ya que esta documentación es interactiva",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=jaw-KAY-stah"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if there are any",
		"back": "en caso de haberlos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the information will be displayed",
		"back": "se desplegará la information",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "by clicking on this box",
		"back": "al darle clic a este recuadro",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "next we see the endpoint route",
		"back": "seguido vemos la ruta del endpoint",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if we click on it, it will open the file",
		"back": "si le damos clic, abrirá el archivo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which points to the file",
		"back": "que apunta al archivo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "just below the title we find a url",
		"back": "justo debajo del titulo encontramos una url",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "first we come across the API name",
		"back": "primero nos encontramos con el nombre de la API",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "pr. --reload",
		"back": "guión, guión, reload",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=gee-UN"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we run it by executing the command",
		"back": "lo corremos ejecutando el comando",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the solution we have created",
		"back": "la solución que tenemos creada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as it grows",
		"back": "a medida que crece",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "high performance",
		"back": "alto rendimiento",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "don't miss the opportunity to take your skills to the next level",
		"back": "no te pierdas la oportunidad de llevar tus habilidades al siguiente nivel",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it is quite similar to this tool",
		"back": "es bastante parecida a esta herramientas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that GitLab provides",
		"back": "que provee GitLab",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the responsibility of each of them",
		"back": "la responsabilidad de cada una de ellas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and see where the changes occur",
		"back": "y ver dónde se producen los cambios",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the first thing that may come to mind",
		"back": "lo primero que nos puede venir a la cabeza",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a bunch of branches",
		"back": "un montón de ramas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you will get to this kind of drawings",
		"back": "vais a llegar a este tipo de dibujos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "anyone who still had a downloaded repository",
		"back": "cualquier persona que tuviera todavía un repositorio descargado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in case the server was lost",
		"back": "en caso de que se perdiera el servidor",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to upload them later",
		"back": "para subirlas luego más tarde",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the windows and the advantages",
		"back": "las ventanas y las ventajas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this has certain advantages",
		"back": "est tiene ciertas ventajas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in such a way that",
		"back": "de tal manera que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if the server goes down",
		"back": "si el servidor se cae",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "performance issues",
		"back": "los problemas de rendimiento",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you could go forward and backward",
		"back": "podías ir adelante y atrás",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "stored in a database",
		"back": "almacenaba en una base de datos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and I was checking the versions",
		"back": "e iba revisando las versiones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "there will be many people you know who",
		"back": "habrá mucha gente de la que conocéis que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the initials of",
		"back": "las siglas de",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "pr. VCS",
		"back": "OO-vay-say-ESS-ay",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a free or paid web service",
		"back": "un servicio web gratuito o de pago",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "your source code",
		"back": "tu código fuente",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "those who want to have a backup of their work",
		"back": "aquellos que quieran tener un respaldo de su trabajo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "what happened here is",
		"back": "lo que sucedió aqui es",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-22 05:01:30",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which would further extend its capabilities",
		"back": "lo que extenderia aún mas sus capacidades",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-22 04:39:25",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a function can be decorated by more than one decorator",
		"back": "una función puede ser decorada por más de un decorador",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-22 04:37:39",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "puede hacer uso de un decorador",
		"back": "you can make use of a decorator",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-21 16:28:42",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "now let's move onto the terminal",
		"back": "ahora pasemos a la terminal",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "will return a result",
		"back": "va a devolver un resultado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "just to give an example",
		"back": "solo para dar un ejemplo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "instead of leaving the number five by default",
		"back": "en vez de dejar el número cinco por defecto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 10:58:52",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "but what if we wanted to add a parameter to it",
		"back": "pero qué pasaría si quisiéramos agregarle un parámetro",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 10:49:14",
		"extras": "conj=querer; pasaría = conditional; quisiéramos = imperfect subjunctive 1; rank=4.93"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the loop function",
		"back": "la función recorrer ciclo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 10:46:34",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which iterates over a range of five",
		"back": "que itera sobre un rango de cinco",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 10:43:49",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that measures time",
		"back": "que mide el tiempo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 10:42:59",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the more optimized the code is, the better the performance will be",
		"back": "cuanto más optimizado esté el código, mejor será el rendimiento",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 19:21:51",
		"extras": "the adjective \"cuanto\" (without accent) describes the noun \"más\";esté is subjunctive of estar"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the time it took",
		"back": "el tiempo que ha tardado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 19:09:43",
		"extras": "conj=tardar; tardar = regular verb"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "how long did the test take",
		"back": "cuánto tiempo demoró la prueba",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 18:52:01",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "how long it took",
		"back": "cuánto tiempo se demoró",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 18:50:01",
		"extras": "conj=demorar; demorar = to delay, to take (time), regular verb"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "when software doesn't receive updates, it becomes vulnerable to attacks",
		"back": "cuando un software no recibe actualizaciones, se vuelve vulnerable a ataques",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 18:45:49",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "where time is measured again",
		"back": "donde se vuelve a medir el tiempo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 18:44:31",
		"extras": "conj=volver; volver = return, become; when followed by \"a medir\" it means \"to do something again\"; conj=medir; medir = to measure, irregular; mido = I measure"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which indicates that",
		"back": "lo que indica que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 16:05:51",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which will be called 001",
		"back": "que se va a llamar 001",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 16:02:47",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "not the received function but the wrapper function",
		"back": "no la función recibida sino la función wrapper",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 16:00:34",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in the following code",
		"back": "en el siguiente código",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 15:54:31",
		"extras": "pr=see-g|ee-EN-tay"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "design pattern",
		"back": "patron de diseño",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 15:51:06",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "are those that receive a function as a parameter",
		"back": "son aquellas que reciben una función como parámetro",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 15:40:29",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if something goes wrong, go directly to tech support",
		"back": "si algo sale mal, vaya directamente al soporte técnico",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 02:38:06",
		"extras": "vaya = affirmative imperitive for Usted; conj=ir; familiar form = ve / no vayas"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "each value that is added",
		"back": "cada valor que se vaya agregando",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 02:36:22",
		"extras": "conj=ir; vaya = subjunctive of ir"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's check if it meets the conditions",
		"back": "revisemos que si cumple con las condiciones",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 02:27:05",
		"extras": "conj=revisar; revisemos is affirmative imperitive (subjunctive); revisamos = we check"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and that is where the items that are added will be saved",
		"back": "y es ahí donde se van a guardar los elementos que sean agregadas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 02:21:47",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to be responsible for adding",
		"back": "que se encargue de agregar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-29 02:13:28",
		"extras": "conj=encargar; encargue is subjunctive; encargar = entrust / order; se encargar = take charge / handle"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "for it to be a closure, there must be a nested function",
		"back": "para que sea un closure, debe haber una función anidada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 22:34:26",
		"extras": "rank=4.9"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "therefore, it has access to the variables",
		"back": "por lo tanto, tiene acceso a las variables",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 22:29:38",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since we have seen what a scope is",
		"back": "ya que hemos visto qué es un scope",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 22:05:32",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "outside of any function",
		"back": "por fuera de cualquier función",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 22:02:23",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if remote access were denied, try to check if the server is offline",
		"back": "si el acceso remoto fuere denegado, intenta verificar si el servidor está fuera de línea",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 21:58:47",
		"extras": "note the difference between \"fuere\" and \"fuera\""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "outside the function",
		"back": "por fuera de la función",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 21:56:11",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "when defining a variable",
		"back": "al definir una variable",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 21:55:06",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "belongs to the local scope of that function",
		"back": "pertenece al scope local de esa función",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 21:16:36",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "any variable that is created",
		"back": "cualquier variable que sea creada",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 21:15:19",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we refer to scope",
		"back": "nos referimos a scope",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 13:33:58",
		"extras": "this is reflexive, the same as \"nosotros nos referimos a scope\""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "funciones anidadas",
		"back": "nested functions",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 13:32:40",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "before understanding what we are referring to",
		"back": "antes de entender a qué hacemos referencia",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-28 13:31:59",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "Paco has traveled 20 units",
		"back": "Paco ha recorrido 20 unidades",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-27 13:25:56",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this time the number 20 has been printed",
		"back": "esta vez se ha impreso el número 20",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-27 13:19:12",
		"extras": "conj=imprimir; both imprimido and impreso are past participles of imprimir"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "whose constructor receives name and age",
		"back": "cuyo constructor recibe nombre y edad",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-27 13:05:07",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "double underscore at the beginning and end",
		"back": "doble guion bajo al inicio y al final",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-27 13:02:49",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "one that belongs to this",
		"back": "uno que pertenece a esto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-27 12:40:56",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the code is a little more readable and easier to understand",
		"back": "el código es un poco más legible y facíl de entender",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-25 15:34:07",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "since inherited classes can take advantage of functions that already exist in the parent class",
		"back": "ya que las clases heredadas pueden aprovechar funciones que ya existen en la clase padre",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-25 15:32:44",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it is important to highlight that",
		"back": "es importante resaltar que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-25 15:30:32",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "arguments required by the parent class",
		"back": "argumentos requeridos por la clase padre",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-25 15:25:45",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we can override the characteristics",
		"back": "podemos sobrescribir las características",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-25 15:22:40",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "with the class statement",
		"back": "con la sentencia class",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-25 15:13:32",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it also has two methods",
		"back": "también cuenta con dos métodos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-25 15:09:10",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "they have methods of the class from which they are created",
		"back": "tienen métodos de la clase a partir de la cual son creadas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-25 14:46:22",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this time we got an error",
		"back": "esta vez nos ha salido un error",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:55:29",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "name, surname and age",
		"back": "nombre, apellido y edad",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:51:30",
		"extras": "pr=ah-peh-JEE-doh"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "they depend on the object being created",
		"back": "dependen del objeto que está siendo creado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:48:40",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and we are going to assign the value 5 to this one",
		"back": "y a esta le vamos a asignar el valor 5",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:44:07",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that are being represented in the code",
		"back": "que se están representando en el código",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:42:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "through which objects are constructed",
		"back": "a través de los cuales se construyen los objetos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:39:02",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is called cloud storage",
		"back": "a esto se le llama almacenamiento en la nube",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:37:43",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is called open source",
		"back": "a esto se le dice código abierto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:37:05",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is called machine learning",
		"back": "a esto se le llama machine learning",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:36:25",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "classes are plans or templates",
		"back": "las clases son los planos o plantillas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:34:56",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "these are known as methods",
		"back": "a esto se le conoce como métodos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:33:49",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "hence",
		"back": "por lo que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:07:07",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and add it to the total",
		"back": "y se la suma al total",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:06:07",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in addition, each object has behaviors",
		"back": "además, cada objeto tiene comportamientos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:02:43",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which is known as a class",
		"back": "al que se le conoce como clase",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 08:00:59",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "with which we will work",
		"back": "con los cuales vamos a trabajar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-24 07:58:37",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it is important to highlight that",
		"back": "es importante resaltar que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 18:17:51",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and see what happened",
		"back": "y ver qué es lo que sucedió",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 18:12:01",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we run it by typing mypy",
		"back": "lo corremos escribiendo mypy",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 18:07:10",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we also saw how to write",
		"back": "también vimos cómo escribir",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 17:12:06",
		"extras": "vimos = preterite; vemos = present"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "hyphen, greater-than",
		"back": "guión, mayor que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 15:12:22",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in brackets",
		"back": "entre corchetes",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 13:45:58",
		"extras": "pr=kor-CHAY-tahs"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it is composed of",
		"back": "está compuesta de",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 13:39:37",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the following list of surnames",
		"back": "la siguiente lista de apellidos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 11:44:52",
		"extras": "pr=ah-peh-GEE-dohs"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "Python has the mypy library",
		"back": "Python cuenta con la librería mypy",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 11:25:25",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as if it were statically typed",
		"back": "como si fuese tipado estático",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 11:17:05",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "concepts related to the typing of a language",
		"back": "conceptos relacionados al tipado de un lenguaje",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 11:00:46",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if we click on the button",
		"back": "si hacemos clic en el botón",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 10:57:44",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's open a course page",
		"back": "abramos la página de un curso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 08:19:13",
		"extras": "conj=abrir; abramos = affirmative imperitive"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "managing databases with an ORM",
		"back": "el manejo de bases de datos con un ORM",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 08:13:28",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in work environments",
		"back": "en entornos laborales",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 08:12:05",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we will cover advanced topics",
		"back": "abordaremos temas avanzados",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 08:11:06",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "take your Python skills to the next level",
		"back": "llevar tu habilidades en Python al siguiente nivel",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-23 08:10:01",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "on your own or with your team",
		"back": "por tu cuenta o con tu equipo de trabajo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "now you have a repository ready",
		"back": "ahora ya cuentas con un repositorio listo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "as we saw previously",
		"back": "como vimos previamente",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this application as such",
		"back": "esta aplicación como tal",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "but you can see how",
		"back": "pero puedes darte cuenta como",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it is required to maintain control",
		"back": "se requiere mantener un control",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "for which we will need",
		"back": "para lo cual necesitaremos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "but enough of theory",
		"back": "pero basta de teoría",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if you click on the button",
		"back": "si pulsas en el botón",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "having everything under one roof",
		"back": "teniendo todo bajo un mismo techo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=TAY-choh"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "promote the reuse of components",
		"back": "fomentar el reúso de componentes",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this makes more sense (with tomar)",
		"back": "esto toma más coherencia",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this makes more sense (with tener)",
		"back": "esto tiene más sentido",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "hence the name",
		"back": "de allí el nombre",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "a set of tools",
		"back": "un conjunto de herramientas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and take your React skills to the next level",
		"back": "y lleva tus habilidades con React",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "deliver robust code with higher quality",
		"back": "entregar código robusto con mejor calidad",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I will guide you through the setup",
		"back": "te guiaré en la configuración",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=GEE-ahr-ray"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that will help you save time",
		"back": "que te ayudará a ahorrar tiempo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "test your app",
		"back": "probar tu aplicación",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "although we can also make use of some design patterns",
		"back": "aunque también podemos echar mano de algunos patrones de diseño",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "very close to reaching the end",
		"back": "muy cerca de llegar al final",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "dónde se va a encontrar",
		"back": "where will you find it",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the moment we stop using this hook",
		"back": "en el moment en que dejemos de utilizar este hook",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "from that moment on we will continue listening",
		"back": "a partir de eso momento vamos a seguir escuchando",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=say-GEER"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we already have it enabled",
		"back": "ya lo tenemos habilitado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "is not available yet",
		"back": "no está disponible aún",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "that is",
		"back": "o sea",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to save us possible problems",
		"back": "para ahorrarnos posibles problemas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if not, it may cause you problems",
		"back": "si no, te puede dar problemas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I tried it inside Google Chrome",
		"back": "yo probé dentro de Google Chrome",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "upward and downward",
		"back": "hacia arriba y hacia abajo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "every time the mouse moves",
		"back": "cada vez que se mueva el mouse",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "what I'm going to need is",
		"back": "lo que voy a necesitar es",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I'm going to leave it empty",
		"back": "lo voy a dejar el vacío",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "note=dejar is regular"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I'm going to take advantage of the situation",
		"back": "voy a aprovechar la situación",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it counts as a React function",
		"back": "cuenta como una función de React",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "they are still at a very basic point",
		"back": "todavía se encuentran en un punto muy basico",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which is based on this other component",
		"back": "el cual está basado en este otro componente",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I'm showing you",
		"back": "te estoy mostrando",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we no longer need to think so much about it",
		"back": "ya no necesitamos pensar tanto en eso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and I'm binding it so that this method runs",
		"back": "y lo estoy vinculando para que se ejecute este método",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and that's all",
		"back": "y eso es todo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and I bring it to my functional component",
		"back": "y lo traigo a mi componente funcional",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=trah-EE-goh"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this is going to work for us",
		"back": "esto nos va a funcionar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if you notice, as I was mentioning to you",
		"back": "si te fijas, como te estaba mencionando",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "note=fijar: to fasten, regular"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we are going to completely ignore this part",
		"back": "vamos a ignorar por completo esta parte",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's analyze the constructor part",
		"back": "analicemos la parte del constructor",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we are still missing some parts",
		"back": "aún nos faltan algunos partes",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in theory",
		"back": "en teoria",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "which makes these processes much easier",
		"back": "que vuelve mucho más fáciles estos procesos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "note=vuele present of volver, to return"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "let's see the great advantages it has",
		"back": "vayamos viendo las grandes ventajas que tiene",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "note=vayamos subjuctive of ir"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "for which hooks were created",
		"back": "por las cuales se crearon los hooks",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I wouldn't do this",
		"back": "yo no hiciera esto",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "pr=JOE-no; alternative=yo no haría esto (conditional)"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "if we look here",
		"back": "si nos fijamos acá",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": "note=fijar: to fasten, fix to a spot, regular"
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "another important detail is that",
		"back": "otro detalle importante es que",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "within the rest of the application",
		"back": "dentro del resto de la aplicación",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "inheritance is a concept of OOP",
		"back": "la herencia es un concepto de OOP",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "display it within the document",
		"back": "desplegarla dentro del documento",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I'm going to come here",
		"back": "yo voy a venir acá",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so for example",
		"back": "así que, por ejemplo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and it is referring us to this method that is here",
		"back": "y nos la está refiriendo a este método que está acá",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "is taking the scope of this class",
		"back": "está tomando el alcance de esta clase",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "this method does not exist yet",
		"back": "aún no existe este método",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "trace what the input was",
		"back": "rastrear cuál fue el input",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "is an empty text string",
		"back": "es una cadena de texto vacía",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "so let's get to work",
		"back": "así que vamos a poner manos a la obra",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "according to the selection that appears here",
		"back": "según la selección que aparece acá",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "state management",
		"back": "el manejo del estado",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and we see what is going to be shown",
		"back": "y vemos que se va a mostrar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "besides that",
		"back": "además de eso",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "memory leak",
		"back": "fuga de memoria",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I have to press right click",
		"back": "tengo que presionar clic derecho",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to debug",
		"back": "depurar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "everything is ready now",
		"back": "ya se encuentra todo listo",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "I'll show you a couple quickly",
		"back": "te voy a mostrar un par rápidamente",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "fits the name",
		"back": "calza con el nombre",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "and search here",
		"back": "y acá buscar",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "debug mode",
		"back": "el modo de depuración",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "in case you don't",
		"back": "en caso de que no",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "you have to drag that folder",
		"back": "tienes que arrastrar esa carpeta",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "address the problems",
		"back": "abordar los problemas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the concept behind hooks",
		"back": "el concepto que está detrás de los hooks",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conj: decir;present",
		"back": "digo, dices, dice, decimos, decís, dicen",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "conj: decir;preterite",
		"back": "dije, dijiste, dijo, dijimos, dijisteis, dijeron",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "just as his name says",
		"back": "tal como su nombre el dice",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "the same goes for events",
		"back": "lo mismo ocurre con los eventos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "we replace it with a single line",
		"back": "lo reemplazamos por una solo línea",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "very similar",
		"back": "muy parecidas",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "what I'm showing you here",
		"back": "que te estoy mostrando acá",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "before starting I would like to talk to you about what they are",
		"back": "antes de comenzar quisiera hablarte sobre qué son",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "it will be a pleasure to be your instructor",
		"back": "será un gusto ser tu instructor",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "to debug and prevent possible errors",
		"back": "a depurar y prevenir posibles errores",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "es",
		"front": "stop using patterns unnecessarily complex",
		"back": "dejar de usar patrones innecesariamente complejos",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-01 00:00:00",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "to learn how to design",
		"back": "pour apprendre à concevoir",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-15 08:22:19",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "it is now possible",
		"back": "il est désormais possible",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-14 08:54:58",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "I define the first route",
		"back": "je définis le premiere route",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 08:42:25",
		"extras": "présent and passé simple: je définis"
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "since we will add more as we go along",
		"back": "puisqu'on va en ajouter au fur et à mesure",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 08:37:39",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "as is customary on Python projects",
		"back": "comme il est d'usage sur les projets Python",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 08:20:38",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "you will learn how to sketch and structure your web applications",
		"back": "tu apprendras à esquisser et à structurer tes applications web",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-30 08:18:20",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "GitHub Actions is everything that revolves around CI and CD",
		"back": "GitHub Actions est tout ce qui gravite autour de la CI et la CD",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:59:01",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "a license that is affixed to the project",
		"back": "une licence qui est apposée sur le projet",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:56:24",
		"extras": "rank=4.88"
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "so if you are not comfortable with GitHub",
		"back": "donc si vous n'êtes pas à l'aise avec GitHub",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:54:12",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "a company that offers hosting services",
		"back": "une entreprise qui propose des services d'hébergement",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:48:56",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "since in fact",
		"back": "puisqu'en effet",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:43:10",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "if you want to make your deployments easier",
		"back": "si vous souhaitez faciliter vos déploiements",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:25:31",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "the development of business applications",
		"back": "le développement d'applications métier",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:24:01",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "it is strongly recommended to have prior knowledge of GitHub",
		"back": "il est vivement recommandé de connaître préalable GitHub",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:22:14",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "note however that in order to approach this training",
		"back": "notez toutefois qu'afin d'aborder cette formation",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:18:57",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "the implementation of tools",
		"back": "la mise en place d'outils",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:13:10",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "this in order to make your projects more reliable",
		"back": "cela afin de fiabiliser vos projets",
		"whenCreated": "2024-12-18 09:16:07",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "on the one hand it affects",
		"back": "d'une part ça touche",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-12 01:41:56",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "all of the requests",
		"back": "l'ensemble des requêtes",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-12 01:39:44",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "avoid putting display logic inside your controllers",
		"back": "éviter de mettre de la logique d'affichage au sein de tes contrôleurs",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 23:03:11",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "it's starting from nothing",
		"back": "c'est en partent de rien",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 22:50:06",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "this saves you from having to redevelop",
		"back": "ça t'évite d'avoir à rédevelopper",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 22:47:22",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "since these are languages ​​that are compiled",
		"back": "vu que c'est des langues qui sont compilés",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:41:17",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "a tree view of the folders",
		"back": "une vue en arbre des dossiers",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:38:15",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "I can hit escape to cancel",
		"back": "je peux faire échap pour annuler",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:36:18",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "tu as des raccourcis ici",
		"back": "you have shortcuts here",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:29:40",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "which is displayed",
		"back": "qui s'affiche",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:27:57",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "as soon as you have it installed",
		"back": "dès que tu l'as installé",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:27:03",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "is supposed to directly detect",
		"back": "est censé directement détecter",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:25:52",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "for a whole set of languages",
		"back": "pour tout un ensemble de langages",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:23:48",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "throughout this training",
		"back": "tout au long de cette formation",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:11:23",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "you have all the videos",
		"back": "tu as l'ensemble des videos",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:10:08",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "from then on",
		"back": "dès lors",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-10 21:08:45",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "is my audio off or on",
		"back": "est-ce que mon audio est activé ou désactivé",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:55:07",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "is my light off or on",
		"back": "est-ce que ma lumière est éteinte ou allumée",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:54:43",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "maybe I can log in already here",
		"back": "je peux peut-être déjà me connecter ici",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:24:45",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "we will discover the components",
		"back": "découvrirons les composants",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:18:57",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "at the same time",
		"back": "en même temps",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:14:28",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "you are in the right place",
		"back": "tu es au bon endroit",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:13:52",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "used throughout the world",
		"back": "utilisé à travers le monde",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:12:09",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "reliable applications",
		"back": "des applications fiables",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:10:43",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "I don't have to record every phrase",
		"back": "je n'ai pas besoin d'enregistrer chaque phrase",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:09:54",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "perhaps we could change the number of phrases that are displayed",
		"back": "peut-être pourrions-nous changer le nombre de phrases affichées",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:07:15",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "I have the browser tab here",
		"back": "j'ai l'onglet du navigateur ici",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:06:23",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "I have to start the audio over again",
		"back": "je dois recommencer l'audio",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:04:30",
		"extras": ""
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "we have an interview today, we have to remember that",
		"back": "nous avons une interview aujourd'hui, nous devons nous en souvenir",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:01:46",
		"extras": "pr=noozeñ"
	},
	{
		"language": "fr",
		"front": "perhaps it could be a reminder",
		"back": "peut-être que cela pourrait être un rappel",
		"whenCreated": "2025-01-07 08:00:30",
		"extras": ""
	}
]